《深水》
带我去月球遨游
Fly me to the moon
让我尽情嬉戏
And let me play
在繁星之间穿梭
among the stars
让我瞧瞧春日的模样
Let me see what spring is like
在木星与火星之上
On Jupiter and Mars
换言之
In other words
请对我真心
please be true
换言之 我爱你
In other words, I love you
你 你 还有你
You, you, and you
我们仨
The three of us
大家给里奇捧个场
Let's give it up for Rich
这招永远经典
That one never gets old
他是在跟我说话 没理你 唱得好啊 机长 太赞了 你可真够呛
He's talking to me, not you. Beautiful voice, Captain. So good. You are terrible.
你知道我最不擅长什么吗？结婚这事儿
You know what I'm terrible at? Marriage.
初次约会我倒挺在行
I'm pretty good at first dates.
嘿 宝贝 我……哦 老天保佑
Hey honey, I, oh thank God.
我还以为赶不上见你了
I thought we missed you.
我收到你的信息了
I got your message.
对 他们改了排班
Yeah, they changed the roster.
你什么时候回来？
When are you coming back?
亲爱的 我拿到新班表就发给你 本
Babe, I'll send you a new schedule when I get it. Ben.
我知道你很难过
I know you're hurting.
我们都一样
We both are.
但你不能总
But you can't keep
逃避现实 等等 亲爱的
running away from that. Hold on, babe.
嘿 丽莎 有消息了吗？
Hey Lisa, you found me something?
有条洛杉矶到上海的航线
There's an LA Shanghai route.
但我不太确定
But I don't know,
很快就要起飞了
it's leaving soon.
行 我接了
All right, I'll take it.
你没时间回家了
You won't have time to go home.
无所谓 我接了
Doesn't matter, I'll take it.
嘿 纳丁打进来了
Hey, I got Nadine on the other line.
我待会儿打给你 行吗？
I'll call you back, all right?
宝贝 妈 你们在哪儿呢？
Honey, Mom, where are you?
儿子病了
Our son is sick.
本 他现在需要你
Ben, he needs you here.
噢 我得走了 妈妈 娜丁 肖恩在喊我
Oh, I gotta go. Mom, Nadine, Sean's calling.
导演 雷尼·哈林
先生 这儿禁止吸烟
Sir, you can't smoke here.
电影院、飞机、酒吧 在我连在外面抽根烟都要被这些扫兴的家伙骚扰
Cinemas, planes, bars. Now I can't even smoke outside without being harassed by the fun police.
拜托啊 先生
Come on, sir.
吸烟区就在那边
The designated smoking areas are located right over there.
上帝啊
god.
嘿 里奇
Hey, Rich.
看来我是你飞上海的副驾驶 好久不见
It looks like I'm your right seat to Shanghai. Been a while.
听说你要退休了 谢了 给你 佩妮
I heard you're hanging it up. Thank you. Here you go, Penny.
嘿 昨晚唱K你没来啊
Hey, you missed karaoke night.
听说你又唱了那首老歌 靠 管用吗？每次都管用 谢了
I hear you sang that same song again. Damn. Did it work? It always works. Thank you.
抱歉 先生 请这边走
Sorry, sir. Please step this way.
该死 我这儿还有个随机的
Hell, I've got a random
登机口见
Meet you guys at the gate
请便 请便 你好吗 佩妮？挺好的 你呢？
Go ahead. Go ahead. How you doing, Penny? Good. How are you?
你信任我来驾驶这架飞机吗？
You trust me to captain a plane?
你是在担心我的机长资质吗？
You worried about my test phase?
先生 包里有没有电池或者充电宝？
Any batteries or power banks, sir?
呃 没有 真的不能给我升个舱吗？
Uh, no. Sure I can't get upgraded?
我可是金卡会员 你知道吧
I'm a gold member, you know.
我不想坐 你知道我一坐飞机就紧张
I don't want to. You know how I get with flying.
行 听着 我们非得在这儿说这个吗？
Okay, look, do we have to do this here?
我不想说 就在这儿说 我告诉你：你根本不明白
I don't want to. Right here. Tell you what: You don't get it.
去上海的飞机更大 不对 才没有
The plane is bigger to Shanghai. No, they're not.
比你以前坐过的都大 行吧 那也算个好消息 对吧？
Than the ones you've previously been on. Okay. That's something, right?
你们没事吧？嗯 没事
You folks okay? Yeah, it's fine.
我女儿害怕坐飞机
My daughter doesn't like flying.
你知道有什么比坐飞机更危险吗？
You know what's more dangerous than flying on an airplane?
河马
Hippos.
骗人 你瞎编的吧 自己上网查
No way. You made that up. Google it.
你会没事的 除非有人偷偷带了一头河马上来
You're gonna be fine. Unless someone smuggles a hippo onboard.
你是机长吗？
Are you like a captain
不 我是副驾驶
No, I'm a first officer
我的职责就是保证机长飞行路线笔直
It's my job to make sure the captain flies straight
都这把年纪了还不是机长 科拉  不觉得尴尬吗？够呛吧？的确
Aren't you too old not to be a captain, Cora? Tough, huh? Yeah.
嗯 科拉 人生嘛 有时候
Well, Cora, sometimes in life
总得绕几条弯路 才能抵达想去的地方
you gotta take a few detours to get where you're going
你走过弯路吗？没有 我极度守时
You ever had to take a detour? No, I'm extremely punctual.
乖女孩
Good girl.
她很硬气 我知道 谢了 科拉 科拉 科拉 科拉 快看
She's tough. I know. Thank you, Cora. Cora, Cora, Cora, look.
快看妈妈给我买了啥 嘿 大家快看快看
Look what Mama got me. Hey guys, look, look.
那玩意儿就不能小声点吗？就是 够酷吧？
Could that thing be any louder? I know. Cool, right?
我还给它换了个新电池
And I got a new battery for this.
好了 搞定 给他脖子上植个宠物芯片就行
Okay, there we go. Just put a pet chip in his neck.
科拉 你介意吗？
Cora, do you mind?
我正忙着呢 待会儿还你 别急 密码是他生日
I was doing something. I'll give it back. Just hang on. The password's his birthday.
听着 科拉宝贝 这趟旅行你得看好你弟弟 行吧？是继弟
Listen, Cora honey, we're gonna need you to look out for your brother on this trip, okay? Stepbrother.
好了 就这些了 这是最后一件
That's it. That's the last of this.
装载完毕
Load it up
谢谢 东北航空140次航班 飞往上海 现在开始登机 嘿 嘿
Thank you. Northeastern Airlines Flight 140 to Shanghai will now begin boarding. Hey hey.
哥们儿 千万别吐我一身
Don't you dare puke on me, bro.
信不信我把你扔这儿 我可没开玩笑
I'll drop your drunk ass right here. I'm not playing.
天哪 电竞
Oh gosh. Esports
打游戏也算运动？
Playing video games isn't a real sport.
不就是一群loser宅在妈妈家地下室 嚼着薯片……
It's a bunch of losers kicking it in Mommy's basement with bags of Doritos and...
哦 抱歉 借过一下 哟 电竞小子？松手
Oh, I'm sorry. Excuse me. Ooh. What's up, Esports? Let go.
把你的脏手拿开！哇哦 行 抱歉
Get your hands off her. Whoa. Okay. Sorry.
他只是喝高了 哟 这小妞够劲儿 我喜欢 别碰她
He's just a little drunk. Ooh. She's feisty. I like it. Don't touch her.
你想怎么着啊 键盘侠？
What are you gonna do about it, Captain Keyboard?
哈奇 你这个没教养的蠢货给我放尊重点
Hutch, get your disrespectful dumbass in line.
这是对女士说话的态度吗？教练 交给我 闭嘴 杰西
Is this how we talk to a lady? Coach, I got this. Shut up, Jesse.
在我的队伍里 我们不能这么丢人 抱歉 女士
Now, this is not how we represent ourselves on my team. My apologies, miss.
借过一下 我本来该升舱的
Excuse you. I should have been upgraded.
再循环风扇已经报修了
Recirc fan is written up.
按规定 修好前我们不能起飞
We can't legally depart until they fix it.
我刚重启过了
I just reset it.
保不齐它一会儿又挂了 嗨 欢迎登机 就在右边
Doesn't mean it won't crap out again later. Hi. Welcome. Just to the right.
你让我们好等啊
You made us wait long enough.
咋了 哥们儿？行 好嘞 走你
What's up, bro? Yeah, okay. There we go.
没错 就在这儿 嘿 我挺好的
Yeah. Here you can. Hey, I'm fine.
来 咱们坐下吧 快点儿 坐下
Let's sit down. Come on. Let's sit down.
要不要系好安全带？
You want to strap in?
各位乘客下午好 我是佩妮 代表东北航空欢迎您登机
Good afternoon, passengers. My name is Penny, and on behalf of Northeastern Airlines, I'd like to welcome you aboard.
麻烦让一让 借过一下
Coming through. Excuse us.
别因为我们打断了你们 抱歉 当我们没来过
And don't let us interrupt. Sorry. We were never here.
先生 麻烦您把座椅靠背调直
Sir, would you please put your seat back up?
当然没问题 欢迎乘坐N140航班 本航班从洛杉矶起飞
Why sure. I would like to welcome you aboard Flight N 140.  Departing from LAX.
目的地是上海 谢谢 我们即将开始起飞程序
And arriving at Shanghai. Thank you. We'll be beginning our departure procedures shortly.
现在
So at this time,
请就座
please take your seats
并确认您的安全带已经系好
and make sure your seat belts are securely fastened.
东北航空140 本航班将从
Northeastern 140, you will depart today
24左跑道起飞
from runway 24L.
起飞前检查单：襟翼 你觉得现在设定在几度？
Before Takeoff Checklist Flaps. Where do you think they're set?
我需要你回答 本 你明明知道
I just need a response. You do know, Ben,
美国联邦航空局规定  我们必须反复确认襟翼
that the FAA has us confirm flaps over and over
就因为达美1141航班上那帮蠢货
only because those idiots flying Delta 1141
光顾着聊想泡哪个空姐
were so busy yakking about which flight attendant they wanted to bang
结果忘了检查 机长
they forgot to check them. Captain,
给个话就行 襟翼五度 本
I just need a response. Flaps are five, Ben.
和之前三次检查的位置一样
Same place as the last three times we checked them.
东北140 允许24左跑道起飞
Northeastern 140, you are cleared for takeoff 24 L.
允许24左起飞 东北140
Clear for takeoff 24 left, Northeastern 140.
再见 机长
See you guys, Captain.
刚才那会儿 你因为检查襟翼的事 是不是想揍我？
It looked like you wanted to take a swing at me over that flap check.
那对我的仕途可没好处
That wouldn't help my career any.
你不就是这么被空军踢出来的？
Isn't that how you got bounced out of the Air Force?
哼 那个高级长官是自作自受
Well, that senior officer had it coming
而你 你就是招人烦
You, you're just annoying
丢了你的退休金和补贴
Blew your pension and your benefits
有老婆孩子要养 日子不好过啊
That's tough with a wife and young kids
只能来了一家破通勤航空公司混口饭吃
Had to catch on with some shitbag commuter airline
现在你却坐在了我的位子上
and now you're in that seat
这本该是我的位置才对
when of course you should be in mine
心里想着自己可不能再犯错了 呵 本 Nand thinking you can't afford to break any more rules. Well, Ben
我肯定不会说出去的
I'm sure not gonna tell.
刚才我揍你一顿 也没人能拿我怎样
So I could have popped you one and gotten away with it
我会告发你的 我就知道你会
I'd rat you out. I know you would.
不加冰 嗯
No ice. Mmm hmm.
怎么了？
What's up?
没啥
Not a lot.
我孙女住上海
My granddaughter lives in Shanghai.
真不错
Awesome.
就是想问问你儿子最近怎么样
I just wanted to check in on how your son's doing.
听说他最近病得不轻
Heard he's been pretty sick lately
你妻子肯定很辛苦
Must be tough on your wife
尤其你还要上班 顾不上家里
especially when you're working and all
嗯 纳丁的家人就住在附近
Yeah well Nadine's family lives nearby
我不在的时候 他们会帮忙照应
They help out when I'm gone
什么鬼
What the fuck
哦 见鬼 数据表明 气流颠簸从未导致过飞机失事
Oh damn it. Statistics say that turbulence has never brought a plane down.
这算是安慰吗？我没事
Is that supposed to be comforting? I'm fine.
我正需要这杯酒提神呢 结果全洒了
I just spilled my gin and tonic when I really need it most.
先生您好 嘿 猜猜我需要什么 抱歉 耳塞没了 完美 真是完美
Hi sir. Hey, take a guess what I need. I'm sorry. We're out of earplugs. That's perfect. Just perfect.
怎么 卫生纸也要限量供应了是吧？你们可真行
What, you're gonna ration out the toilet paper too, huh? You guys are unbelievable.
先生 您不能这么做
Sir, you can't do that.
我听不见
I can't hear you.
嗯
Yeah.
什么？你配不上她 哦不 我不是那个意思 等等 真的？她可是个绝佳的大美女
What? Way out of your league. Oh no. No, I wasn't. Wait. Really? She's a solid nine.
不想打击你 但你顶多五分
Hate to break it to you, but you're a five.
收拾收拾也许能到六分 这已经算给你面子了
Maybe you could scrub up to a six but that's being generous
哦 我快被后面的贝齐·罗打败了
Oh I'm getting destroyed by Betsy Ross back here
等等 万一我性格超好呢？就你？
Wait what if I've got a great personality You don't
哦
Oh
科拉 亲爱的 听着 我知道改变很可怕 好吗？
Cora honey Look I know change is scary okay
但芬恩真的很崇拜你
But Finn really looks up to you
所以你稍微和善一点会死吗？
So would it kill you to be just a little nicer
嘿 是我
Hey it's me
科拉
Cora
爸妈呢 他们去泳池游泳了
Where's Mom and Dad They went to the pool for a swim
飞机上还有游泳池
There's a pool on the plane
对 对 就在后面
Yeah Yeah it's back there
嘿 小朋友 找不到座位吗
Hey little man can't you find your seat
哦 你喜欢玩游戏啊
Oh you into gaming huh
没错 要不要给我露一手
Right You wanna show me how it's done
好 来吧 坐这里 好的
Yeah Come on Here Okay
你的右手放这儿
Your right hand is right here
取消前部货舱火警主警告 确认 收到
I am canceling master warning for forward cargo fire. Confirm. Confirmed.
执行记忆项目 前部货舱火警 明白
Let's do the memory items, forward cargo fire. Copy that.
前货舱灭火开关打开 确认 已确认 释放灭火瓶 确认 已确认
Forward cargo fire switch on. Confirm. Confirmed. Fire bottle discharge on. Confirm. Confirmed.
Pan-pan-pan 东北航空140
Pan-pan-pan, Northeastern 140.
我们前货舱火警警报 并检测到烟雾
We have a fire indication in our forward cargo bay and smoke has been detected.
请告知最近合适机场的航向
We require a heading to the nearest suitable airport.
东北航空140 这里是奥克兰空管中心
Northeastern 140, Northeastern 140, this is KZAK Oakland.
最近的机场是关岛国际机场
Your nearest airport is Guam International.
在你们南边400海里
400 nautical miles south.
叫机长回来 收到 收到 奥克兰 东北航空140
Let's get the captain back here. Roger. Roger. KZAK, Northeastern 140.
我们现在直飞关岛 正在下降到一万英尺 东北航空140
We are now direct Guam, descending at 10,000 feet. Northeastern 140.
你还好吗 亲爱的？嗯 我没事
You okay honey? Yeah, I'm fine.
本 现在什么情况？前货舱着火了
Ben, what do we have here? Forward cargo fire.
记忆项目已执行 灭火瓶没反应 我已宣布紧急状态
We've completed the memory items. Fire bottles aren't discharging. I've declared an emergency.
我们正在下降到一万英尺 转向关岛国际机场
We're descending to 10,000, redirecting to Guam International.
下去 把火灭了
Get down there. Put it out.
收到
Roger.
爸
Dad.
爸 你在里面吗？
Dad, are you in there?
火焰瞬间演变成了爆炸
The fire turned into an explosion.
搞什么鬼？
What the hell?
客舱失火了 情况越来越糟 准备迫降
We lost the cabin. This isn't getting any better. Taking her down.
快 快 抓住面罩
Come on, come on, grab them.
快戴上
Put it on, come on.
把这个戴上 好的
Put this on. Okay.
里奇 快戴面罩
Rich, put your mask on.
本 等你戴好 我们都飞到一万英尺平飞了 佐伊 戴面罩
Ben, we're gonna be level at 10,000 before you can even get that on. Zoe, get your mask.
一万一千 目标一万 还剩一千
11,000 for 10,000. Thousand to go.
高度一万 到达一万英尺
Level 10,000. I see 10,000.
飞机稳定了 仪表正常 接管飞机 我要广播了 我接手 确认
We're stable. Instruments responsive. Take the aircraft. I'm gonna make a PA. My aircraft. Confirmed.
由你操控 确认
Your aircraft. Confirmed.
各位旅客 我是机长
Folks, this is the captain speaking.
货舱起火
We have a fire in the cargo hold.
我们已降至安全高度 正备降关岛国际机场
We've descended to a safe altitude and diverted to Guam International Airport.
请务必保持冷静
It's very important that everybody remain calm.
让一下 让一下 我直接过去
Excuse me, excuse me, I'm coming straight back.
请大家听从乘务员的指示
We need all of you to follow your flight attendant's instructions.
请稍等 我们正在把受影响区域的乘客转移到安全座位
One second as we get passengers near the affected area moved to safer seating.
丽莎 后面还有空位
Lisa, there are more seats at the back.
先生 这边 快走 快走
This way, sir. Go, go.
别动 除非必须...... 丽莎 清空通道
No, no. Don't move unless you have to. Lisa, clear the passage.
我爸妈 现在不行 待在这儿
My parents. Not now. Stay here.
一号引擎失效了 先生 你不能那样 你担心的是这个
We've lost engine one. Sir, you can't do that. You're worried about this.
立刻回你的座位
Get back to your seat right now.
飞行控制失效 液压系统失灵
Flight controls don't respond. Hydraulics are gone.
别跟我说哪里坏了
Don't tell me what's broken.
告诉我这架飞机上还有什么还能用
Tell me what still works on this jet.
手动缆线还能控制外侧副翼、升降舵和方向舵 动手吧
You have manual cables to the outboard ailerons, elevator, and rudder. Let's get to it.
求救 求救 求救 东北航空140 一号引擎失效 140 关岛国际
Mayday Mayday Mayday Northeastern 140 We lost engine one 140 Guam International
仍是最近的机场
is still the closest option
我们需要找个更近的机场
We need something closer
140 我们没别的了
140 we have nothing
你们在公海上空
You're over open ocean
救救我们
Help us Help
仪表指针全部归零 我们切换到备用仪表
Instrument needles all rolling back to zero We're on standby instruments
求救 求救 求救 这里是东北航空140 我们失去动力
Mayday Mayday Mayday This is Northeastern 140 We've lost power
机长 无线电失灵了
Captain we lost the radio
关掉辅助动力装置  收到
Stop the APU Roger
没事 坚持住 好吗
It's okay Just hold on okay
再试一次
Hit it again
不行 又试了一次 辅助动力装置还是没启动
Nothing Again APU is not coming up
高度6000英尺
We're at 6,000 feet
试试手动释放冲压空气涡轮 冲压空气涡轮 确认
Try manual deployment of RAT Ram Air Turbine Confirmed
冲压空气涡轮启动 仪表恢复 重启发动机
Ram Air Turbine working Instrument's back online Relight the engine
点火
Ignition
再试一次
Hit it again
不
No
爸 你在哪儿 不 不 不 等等 等等 过来 放开我 放开我
Dad, where are you? No, no, no. Wait, wait. Come here. Let me go. Let me go.
我们会没事的 再试试
We'll be all right. Try it again.
不行 空速不够 无法重新点火
It's not working. We don't have enough airspeed to relight.
也没有空间俯冲加速
And no breathing room to dive for more.
我们要弃机了 开始放油
We're gonna ditch. Start dumping the fuel.
放弃重启引擎 快 马上执行！放油！
We're giving up on the relight. Do it. Do it now. Dumping fuel.
各位旅客 我是机长
This is the captain speaking.
做好防冲击姿势！
Brace for impact.
抱紧！低头！别抬头！
Brace, brace. Heads down. Stay down.
抱紧！低头！
Brace, brace. Heads down.
好 趴下！快趴下！
Okay, okay. Get down. Get down.
（毛利语对话）
SPEAKING MAORI
本 每下降一千英尺 报一次高度和空速
Ben, I want altitude and airspeed callouts every thousand feet.
高度3000英尺 空速220 太快了 该死！
3,000 feet, airspeed 220. Too damn fast.
我看到海浪了 得向右转
I have a visual reference to swells. We gotta come right.
里奇 检查单上说平行于海浪就行 浪不算太大
Rich, the checklist says we just parallel with the swells. Swells aren't that bad.
我需要尽可能大的顶风来降低下降速度
I want all the headwind I can get to slow vertical down rate
里奇 要是机翼太低打到水面 飞机会打滚的
Rich, if we go wing low and catch a tip, we're gonna cartwheel
但要是入水速度太快 我们肯定没命
And if I hit the water too fast, we're done for sure
里奇 你就告诉我风往哪边吹浪 转方向！
Just tell me which way the wind is blowing those swells, Rich. Turn the airplane
我们要平行于海浪迫降
We're gonna land parallel to the swells
我们得向右转30度 确认
We gotta come right 30 degrees. Confirm
确认
Confirmed
收到 我这就去处理那个问题 明白
Bug that heading for me. Roger that
2000英尺 空速190 需要放襟翼吗？
2,000 feet. Airspeed 190. You want flaps?
尽可能多地给我 襟翼开到最大
As much as you can give me. Flaps at maximum
1000英尺 空速180 还是太快了
1,000 feet. Airspeed 180. Still too fast
空速170
Airspeed 170
起落架收起 辅助动力装置灭火系统启动
Landing gear up. APU fire suppression
注意机翼 高度300英尺 空速仍为170
Watch your wings. 300 feet. Airspeed still 170
本 把座位调到最靠后 系紧安全带
Ben, move your seat all the way back. Tighten your harness
里奇 保持那侧机翼上扬
Rich, keep that wing up
我将向左偏10度 机尾下降 机尾下降 高度100英尺
I'm gonna bug you left 10 degrees. Tail down. Tail down. 100 feet
来吧 姑娘 配合我一下
Come on, girl. Work with me.
本 把你的座位调到最后面 照做
Ben, move your seat all the way back. Do it.
准备迎接冲击
Brace for impact.
哦 糟糕
Oh, shit.
救命 谁来帮帮我
Help me. Help.
求你了
Please.
来人啊 帮帮忙
Somebody help.
有人吗？救命！
里奇
Rich.
醒醒 里奇
Wake up, Rich.
你成功了！要不是那片珊瑚礁挡道 咱们现在早开香槟庆祝了
You did it. If it wasn't for that coral reef, we'd be popping champagne right now.
你没事吧？没事
You okay? Yeah.
好的
Okay.
嘿 嘿
Hey. Hey.
你待在这儿别动 我马上回来 好 好
You stay here, okay? And I'll be right back. Okay. Okay.
我的天！里奇 抓住他的胳膊
Oh, my God. Rich, grab him by the arms.
我试试把他弄出来 好
I'll try to get him loose, okay.
一、二、三！不 不 不 停！
One, two, three. No, no, no. Stop.
那样行不通
That's not going to work.
嘿 你会没事的 里奇
Hey, you're gonna be okay, Rich.
我们会把你救出来的
We're gonna get you out of here.
伙计 时间不多了 别紧张 里奇 你的腿被卡住了
Guys, we don't have much time. Easy, Rich. Your leg's pinned.
用斧头砍断 你说什么？
Crash ax. What?
你休想
Don't even think about it.
不 你不能锯我的腿 还没到那一步
No, you're not taking my leg. Not yet.
你可以用它把我撬出来
You can use it to pry me out.
丽莎
Lisa.
丽莎 丽莎
Lisa, Lisa.
丽莎
Lisa.
嘿 小家伙 嘿 嘿
Hey, little guy. Hey, hey.
好了 对 好 我得把这个弄开 好 好了 好了
Okay. Yeah. Okay, I have to get this off. Okay. All right, all right.
你没事了 过来 看着我 没事了 对
You're okay. Come here. Look at me. It's okay. Yeah.
喂 有人吗？
Hello. Anybody?
喂？
Hello?
喂？喂？有人吗？
Hello? Hello? Anybody?
我在这儿 嘿
I'm here. Hey.
撑住 好的 有人来了 有人来救我们了
Hold on. Okay. Yeah. Someone's here. Someone here.
那位好心的女士会来的 她会帮我们的 没错
The nice lady. She's gonna come. She's gonna help us. Yeah.
她知道该怎么做 好的 没错
She knows what to do. Okay. Yeah.
深呼吸 深呼吸 深呼吸
Breathe, breathe, breathe.
没事的
It's okay.
这可不是免费的
没出来
你流了很多血
You're losing a lot of blood.
伙计们 我们得快点
Guys, we have to move fast.
他被卡住了
He's trapped.
别无他法了
There's no other way.
他会失血过多而死 本 这样不行 别犯傻了
He's gonna bleed to death. Ben, it's no good. Don't be a chump.
不管怎样 我都完了 而且 这正是我该待的地方
Either way, I'm done, and I'm exactly where I belong.
少跟我扯什么该待的地方
Don't give me that where I belong crap
你待在这里会死的 出去 你们两个都出去 把门锁上
You stay here you die. Get out. Both of you. Lock the door.
如果水涌进来时那扇门没关 整个飞行甲板都会被淹
If that's open when this water breaks in, we'll flood the entire flight deck
我们所有人都会被拖下水 我要锯掉你的腿
and drag everybody to the bottom. I'm taking your leg.
跟这个从来不按规矩办事的混蛋一起淹死在这里 你谁也救不了
You won't save any lives by drowning in here with some dickhead who always refuses to follow simple protocol.
飞机归你操纵了 本 我不会丢下你 里奇
It's your plane, Ben. I'm not leaving you, Rich.
我不会丢下你
I'm not leaving you.
收到
Confirm.
收到 回家去吧 本
Confirmed. Go home, Ben.
陪陪你儿子
Be with your son.
谢谢你
Thank you.
本 检查ELT 检查应急信标
Ben, the ELT. Check the ELT.
宝贝 哦 宝贝
Honey. Oh, honey.
没事了
It's okay.
没事了 要不要过来坐会儿？
It's okay. Do you want to come and sit down?
佩妮 搭把手
Penny, help me.
把她扶起来
Lift her up.
你没事吧？没事 没事
You okay? Yeah. Yeah.
德克兰
Declan
德克兰 德克兰 快醒醒
Declan, Declan, wake up.
德克兰 快醒醒！
Declan, wake up.
靠
Shit.
这特么到底怎么回事？
What the fuck is happening?
等等 你还好吗？孩子们 该死
Wait, are you all right? The kids. Fuck.
我们得赶紧撤 不 德克兰 别这样
We got to get out of here. No, Declan, don't.
带我飞向月球
Fly me to the moon
让我在群星间嬉戏
And let me play among the stars
让我看看春天是什么样子
Let me see what spring is like
在木星和火星上
On Jupiter and Mars
换句话说 请真心相待
In other words, please be true
换句话说
In other words,
我爱你
I love you.
我们该怎么办？
What do we do?
寻找幸存者 并拿到那个ELT信标（应急定位发射器）
Find survivors and get that ELT beacon.
贝基 我好像探到脉搏了 贝基
Becky, I think I've got a pulse. Becky.
加油 贝基 快醒醒
Come on, Becky, wake up.
我们得立刻动身 贝基 水位在涨
We have to move right now. Becky, water's rising.
你能把她搬动吗？她差不多150磅重
Can you move her? She's like 150 pounds.
我只有一只胳膊能用力 还得爬到那上面去 150磅？你确定？
I've only got the use of one arm, and I got to get all the way up there. 150 pounds? Really?
我可是当奶奶的人了
I'm a grandmother.
我要救的是这个小家伙
The one I'm gonna help is this little fellow here.
走 我能爬 我可是攀爬高手
Let's go. I can climb. I'm a good climber.
露一手吧 高手
Show us your stuff, hotshot.
好嘞 没问题
Okay. Yep.
他们多久能找到咱们？
How long before they find us?
短则一小时 长则几个小时
Could be an hour or several hours.
前提是他们收到了信号 如果……
That's if they got the signal. If.
如果坠落时 应急定位发射器启动了
If the ELT activated when we went down.
如果没有启动
And if it didn't.
没错 所以我得去游一趟
Yeah. That's why I'm going for a little swim.
在机身中部 我本可以带救生筏 但你可能更需要它
It's in the midsection. I'd take the raft, but you might need it.
让我去吧
Let me go.
我参加过三届威基基海浪游泳赛
Waikiki Roughwater three times
我能行 相信我
I can do this. Okay. Trust me.
嗯 你要去哪儿？
Yeah. Where are you going? Um.
去飞机中部
To the middle of the plane.
我爸妈在那儿吗？
Are my mom and dad there?
我想去 不过宝贝 我得游过去 我能游 但距离太远了 好吧
I want to come. Well, I have to swim, sweetheart. I can swim. It's too far. Okay.
但我会去找你爸妈 我保证
But I will look for your parents. I promise.
还有我弟弟芬恩 他叫芬恩
And my little brother Finn. His name is Finn.
佩妮
Penny.
等你到了那边 发个信号确认一下
When you get out there, signal to confirm
好 确认应急定位发射机正常工作
Okay, that the ELT is working all right.
这要记入日志 对吧？对乘务长来说足够了 首席乘务长
This goes in the log, right? Good enough for purser. Chief Purser.
给 拿着这个 不用 这只会拖累我
Here, take this. No, it'll just slow me down.
嘿 能帮我先拿着这些 等我回来好吗？
Hey. Can you hold on to these for me until I get back?
谢了 在头顶行李架 右侧 20排 好的
Thanks. It's in the overhead, starboard side, row 20. Okay.
按一下开关 确保灯一直亮着 行吗？
Just hit the switch and make sure the light stays on, okay?
嘿 好运
Hey, good luck.
我们会找到你家人的 科拉
We're gonna find your family, Cora.
好的？
Okay.
你能行的 贝基 就在你后面 能手
You can do it, Becky. Right behind you, hotshot.
我担心的是这个大家伙 没错 很好
It's this big lug I'm worried about. Right. Great.
现在轮到雪莉·温特斯说闲话了 哈？
Now I got Shelley Winters talking shit, huh?
让我瞧瞧 老实待着别动
Let me see that. Hold still.
手放这儿 懂了吗？
Put your hand here, okay?
先生！
Sir.
鲨鱼！有鲨鱼！鲨鱼！
Shark! Shark! Shark!
佩妮 有鲨鱼！
Shark, Penny!
佩妮 小心鲨鱼！
Penny, shark!
佩妮！
Penny!
不要！
No!
佩妮 鲨鱼来了！
Shark, Penny!
佩妮！鲨鱼！快！把这个穿上！
Penny! Shark! Shark! Put this on.
有鲨鱼！
Shark!
等等 我的鞋！鞋！
Wait, the shoes! The shoes!
快点儿！
Come on
手别碰水！
Keep your hands out of the water
别 停下 怎么了？
No, stop. What?
这不就是出路吗？快放救生筏！
Isn't this how we get out? Deploy the raft.
我们现在在气泡里！
We are in an air bubble.
撕开封条 咱们就沉船了 不过……
Break the seal and then we sink. But...
行 行 知道了
Yeah, okay, okay. Yeah.
再见
bye
不好意思 好吧
Sorry. Okay.
佩妮！佩妮！有鲨鱼！
Penny! Penny! Shark!
佩妮！水里有鲨鱼！
Penny! Shark in the water!
我们马上来！
We're coming!
佩妮！
Penny!
佩妮！有鲨鱼！
Penny! Shark!
救命！
Help me!
佩妮！
Penny!
佩妮 佩妮 我们马上到！我们马上到！
Penny, Penny, we're coming! We're coming!
快点 把手给我
Come on, give me your hand.
佩妮
Penny.
船要沉了 咱们这到底在哪儿啊？船要沉了
We're sinking. Where the hell are we? We are sinking.
我去……你划了好大一道口子 让我看看 没事儿
What the... You have a huge cut. Let me help you. It's nothing.
往我这边游 往我这边游
Swim to me. Swim to me.
来 我接住你了
Here, I've got you.
好的 过来
OK Come here.
你还好吗？
Are you okay?
感觉如何？好受点了吗？
How's that feel? Less terrible?
谢谢你帮我包扎
Thank you for fixing me up.
还有 关于门的事 我很抱歉
And I'm sorry about the door thing.
是的 我们会没事的
Yeah. We are gonna be okay.
得让这小家伙镇定一下
We've got to calm this one down.
不然 我们马上就会缺氧
Otherwise, we're gonna run out of air, and terribly soon.
嘿 嘿 小家伙
Hey, hey, little man.
你和你家人一起坐飞机吗？
You flying with your family?
我妈和我新爸 还有我姐姐科拉 嗯
My mommy and my new daddy and my sister Cora. Okay.
好 我们帮你找家人
Well, we're gonna help you find your family.
我叫马特 她是贝基 还有佐伊 佐伊 佐伊
I'm Matt. That's Becky. And this is Zoe. Zoe, Zoe.
你叫什么？我叫芬恩 芬恩
And you are? My name is Finn. Finn.
一切都会好起来的 没事的
It's gonna be all right. It's gonna be okay.
别骗人了 你明知道不是这样
Stop saying that when you know it's not true.
我们得往后撤
We have to move back.
大家听好了 我们得往后撤 闭嘴 电竞小子
Guys, we have to move back. Shut up, Esports.
你懂个啥？
What do you know about anything?
这边承重太大了
There's too much weight up here.
救救我们
Help us.
睁大你的眼睛 蠢货 没看到那空姐已经吓懵了吗？
Open your eyes, dumbass. Can't you see the steward's totally fried?
别烦她了 行吗？她只是吓到了
Just leave her alone, okay? She's in shock.
让我来帮你 行吗？你是医生？不 我是兽医
Let me help you, okay? Are you a doctor? No, I'm a veterinarian.
真棒 给她戴上伊丽莎白圈
Great. Put a cone on her.
省得她老舔自己
Stop her from licking herself.
瞧见没 这就是为啥我更喜欢动物而不是人
See, that's why I prefer animals to humans.
我们没多少时间了
We don't have much time
闭嘴 快闭嘴 我们会沉下去的
Shut up. Just shut up. We will sink.
我们全得玩完
We are all going to die.
你让我们咋办？往后撤？撤到哪儿？水里去？减点重吧 这小子说得对
What do you expect us to do? Move back? To where? In the water? Take some weight off. The kid's right.
我们底下有片珊瑚礁
There's a coral reef under us.
说不定能分担点压力 那你去呗
It might take some pressure off it. You go then.
一个人无济于事
One person won't make a difference.
你刚才骂我什么？
What'd you just call me?
他叫我什么？行 行
What did he call me? All right, all right.
都给我消停点  你们俩 埃斯波特说得对
Knock it off, both of you. Esport is right.
行了 走吧
Now come on.
还有没有人要来的？
Anybody else coming?
啊？
Huh?
嘿 等等 杰西 干嘛？
Whoa. Hold up, Jesse. What?
要是出事 下面的人全得困在里面
If this thing goes down, anyone who's down there is gonna be stuck inside.
行了 杰西 别犯二了 兄弟
Okay, Jesse, don't be stupid, bro.
那些伤号和老人根本撑不住 杰西 你给我回来 杰西
Some of these wounded and old people won't make it out there, man. Jesse, come back here. Jesse.
走了 快点 快点
Let's go. Come on, come on.
都走 对 都走 走吧 深呼吸
Everyone's going. Yeah, everyone's going. Go for it. Just breathe.
看来那杯伏特加苏打水是喝不上了
Guess you ain't getting me that vodka soda anytime soon.
教练
Coach.
我扶着你 伤着没？丽莎 丽莎 丽莎 丽莎 还有别人吗？教练 教练
I got you. Are you hurt? Lisa, Lisa, Lisa, Lisa. Is there anyone else? Coach, Coach.
教练
Coach.
别 别 别
No, no, no.
抓他 杰西 快抓他
Grab him, Jesse. Grab him.
动起来 动起来 教练 杰西
Move, move. Coach, Jesse.
过来
Come on.
喂 喂 别紧张
Hey, hey. Take it easy.
你 给我下水
You. Get in the water.
别紧张 别紧张 不 住手 下水 不 下去 我不知道 下水 住手 住手
Take it easy. Take it easy. No, stop. Get in the water. No. Get in. I didn't know. Get in the water. Stop it. Stop it.
住手 求你了 住手
Stop it. Stop it, please.
住手 喂 喂
Stop it. Hey, hey.
这样有什么用？啊？
How is this helping? Huh?
你想活命吗？想吗？
Do you want to live? Do you?
是的  想活就给我保持冷静
Yes, then we need to keep our cool.
告诉我 我们能冷静下来
Tell me we're gonna keep our cool.
我会冷静的
I'm gonna keep my cool.
孩子 来点坚果 优质蛋白
Kid, have some nuts. Good protein.
长身体的男孩需要补充蛋白质
Growing boys need their protein.
妈妈说吃坚果会让我长胖
Mommy says nuts make me fat.
哪有母亲会说出这种话？
What kind of a mother would say a thing like that?
行吧 不管那些坚果了
Okay fine. Screw the nuts.
你究竟几岁了？
How old are you anyway?
你觉得我们还剩多少空气？我快八岁了 你才七岁 太危险了
How much air do you think we have left? Almost eight. You're seven. It's too risky.
我猜应该已经学会上厕所了吧
I presume fully potty trained.
怎么 就这么干等着？门还是关着的
What, so just do nothing? The doors stay shut.
你以为我多大？一百岁？也差不多了
How old do you think I am? A hundred? Pretty close.
待在原地 没人能找到我们
Nobody is going to find us if we stay in here.
嘿 干得漂亮啊各位？已经有点闷了 我们可以游出去
Oh, great job guys, huh? It's already getting stuffy. We could swim.
我先下 游下去找出路
I can go first, swim down and find a way out.
不行 有我在 你别去 我来
No. No, not on my watch. I can do it.
我比你熟悉这架飞机
I know the plane better than you
而且你手腕还骨折了
And you have a broken wrist
是你帮我接好的 记得吧？
Which you made better, remember
来 绑上
Here, strap it
快 时间不多了 快
Come on. We don't have much time. Come on.
好 我四处看看 马上回来 行吗？嗯 嗯 行 好
Okay. So I'm gonna take a look around and then I'm gonna be back in a tick, okay? Yeah. Yeah. Okay. Good.
别走
Don't go.
嘿 芬恩 我走了之后 替我照顾好姑娘们 行吗？
Hey, Finn. You look after the ladies for me while I'm gone, yeah?
行 行 没问题
Okay, okay, okay.
早点回来啊 马特
Hurry back, Matt.
她居然记得我名字 哈？
She remembered my name, huh?
听着 我感觉咱俩有戏
Look, I've got a good feeling about us.
喂 喂 嘿 这边
Hey, hey. Hey, over here.
救命
Help us.
救命啊 这边 有人需要帮助 救命
Help. Over here. There's people that need help. Help.
我女儿 科拉！
My daughter, Cora.
救命
Help.
救命 这怎么可能发生？
Help. How could this happen?
我们这可是在鸟不拉屎的地方
We're in the middle of nowhere.
你怎么就能从天上掉下来呢？
How do you just fall out of the sky?
他们得多久才能来救我们？
How long till they rescue us?
别跟我耍贫嘴 回答问题
Don't be a smart ass. Just answer the question.
听着 我知道的都告诉你 行了吧？八成是你他妈的搞的鬼
Look, I'll tell you what I know, okay? Probably your fucking fault.
你跟这家破航空公司一个德行
You and this shitty airline.
听着 我知道你很生气 想要个说法
Look, you're angry, you want answers.
我会给你交代的 好吗？
You're gonna get them, okay?
说实话 能活着找人算账 我们已经够幸运了
Truth is, we're lucky to be alive to blame somebody.
这趟航班上有257个人
There were 257 souls on this flight.
我数了数 大约就剩咱们30个了
I count maybe 30 of us.
照我看 咱们就一件事要办 就是回家跟家人团聚 明白吗？我们有救生筏
The way I see it, we have one job to do, and that is to get home to see our families. Okay? We have rafts.
咱们得坐上去
We need to get in them.
谁没救生衣 从座底下拿一件 报上名字 我叫哈奇
If you don't have a life jacket, take one from under a seat. Tell me your name. I'm Hutch.
哈奇 帮忙把第二个救生筏拉出来
Hutch, I need you to pull out that second raft.
大家快来帮哈奇  把救生筏推到水里去
Everybody help Hutch get the raft into the water.
卡住了 卡住了！
It's stuck. It's stuck.
来 抓紧这个
Here, hold on to that.
科拉 你就待在这儿 好吗？
Cora, I need you to stay here, okay?
别靠近边上 懂吗？好
Stay away from the edge, all right? Okay.
我去取点东西 嘿 大家都小心点
I'm gonna go get something. Hey, everybody, be careful.
水流很急 注意安全
The tide is moving fast.
那儿有两个
Two there.
行 开始吧 准备好了没？
All right, here we go. Ready?
我觉得搞定了
I think we got it.
好 准备好了没？准备好了没？
All right, ready? Ready?
爸爸！
Daddy!
嘿 回来！这个必须带上 快走 快走 走！走！快快快！走啊！
Hey, come back! We need this. Let's go, let's go. Go! Go! Go, go, go! Let's go!
快离开这儿 谁来帮帮我 加油 宝贝
Let's get out of here. Anybody, please help me. Come on, baby.
搞定了 准备好了没？走 走 走！
We got this. Ready? Go, go, go!
搞定了 一 二 三 拉！爸爸 科拉 使劲拉！
We got this. One, two, three. Pull! Daddy, Cora, pull!
把这个放到木筏上 别松手 爸爸 科拉
Get this onto a raft, don't drop it. Daddy, Cora.
快离开这儿 爸爸 对不起
Let's get out of here. Daddy, I'm sorry.
科拉 科拉 快走 对不起
Cora, Cora, come on. I'm sorry.
离那儿远点 不 老兄 你干嘛呢？怎么打不开？
Get away from there. No, man, what are you doing? Why didn't it open?
不知道 拉那破绳子
I don't know. Pull the goddamn rope.
快点 快点
Come on, come on.
快点
Come on.
喂
Hey.
这儿
Here.
应急定位发射器 什么？那个定位器
The ELT. What? The locator.
我给你的那个盒子呢？在哪？
That box I gave you. Where is it?
你逗我呢吧
You gotta be kidding me.
别这样 老兄 我还指望你呢
Come on, man. I was counting on you.
你只要把它带上救生筏就行
All you had to do was get it on the raft.
行吧 既然这么重要 你倒是自己看着办啊 定位器？他说的什么玩意儿？
Yeah, well, if it was so important, maybe you should've looked after it. Locator? What's he talking about?
那是他们找到我们的关键吧？结果你给弄丢了
Is that what they need to find us? And you lost it.
喂 别赖我 老兄 这是你的责任 机长 喂！那边！喂！
Hey, don't put this on me, man. This was your responsibility, Captain. Hey! Over there! Hey!
这儿 你看见他们了吗？
Here, do you see them?
想想办法啊 没戏
Please do something. No way.
不行 他们可以游到另一个筏子那儿
No, they can swim to the other raft.
水流太急了 他们根本过不去
The current is too strong. They'll never make it.
你没看见我们船里都进水了吗？
Can't you see we're already taking on water?
哇！怎么了？怎么了？
Whoa! What? What?
天哪
Oh my God.
你凭什么做决定？我才是机长 那是我的飞机 哦 那架飞机
Who the hell are you to decide? I'm the captain. It's my plane. Oh, that plane.
干得漂亮 是吧？都是因为你 人死了
Great job, huh? People are dead because of you.
现在你想拿我们的命去冒险 就为了让自己好受点？做梦吧 我们原地不动
And now you want to risk our lives to make yourself feel better? No way. We stay put.
你还敢说自己是机长？
You call yourself a captain, huh?
你连救生筏都开不了
You can't even pilot a raft.
我们必须去救他们
We're going to get them.
你心里明白 如果我们不去 那两个小子会有什么结局 把筏子解开
You know damn well what will happen to those two young men if we don't. Untether these rafts.
不行！喂！
No! Hey!
他打我！你看到了 闭嘴 贱人
He hit me! You're a witness. Shut up, bitch.
听见这位女士说的了 别晃船了 出发
You heard the lady. And stop rocking the raft. Let's go.
我想离开 我们还得在这儿待多久？
I want to go. How much longer do we have to stay here?
但愿马特没跟美人鱼跑了吧
I hope Matt hasn't swum away with a mermaid.
他不会丢下我们的
He wouldn't leave us.
它在等什么？
What's it waiting for?
我们快离开这儿
Let's get out of here.
把手给我 快
Give me your hand. Come on.
加油
Come on.
加油 快 加油
Come on, come on, come on.
又是你们两个啊？
You two again, huh?
好了 我们撤吧 走
All right, let's get out of here. Let's go.
出飞机后 我们将救生衣充气
When we get outside the plane, we inflate our jackets.
像大气球一样 直接浮到水面上 不
They'll take us straight up to the surface like a big balloon. No.
我还需要点时间 你不能留在这儿
I need a little more time. You can't stay here.
我带不了你们俩 你能行的 整天忙这忙那的
I can't take both of you. You can do it. Doing this, doing that.
我总是一直在忙
I'm always trying to keep doing.
自从比尔走后 就觉得没意思了 你懂的
Ever since Bill died, it just gets old, you know.
贝基 对不起
Becky, I'm sorry I am.
但我们必须走了 不 我知道 你带芬恩走 不 你也来 求你了
But we have to go now. No, I know. You take Finn. No, you come too. Please.
你坚强点 高手 我欣赏你的范儿 别管我
You stay strong, hotshot. I admire your style. Don't worry about me.
我会回来的 贝基 我发誓
I will come back, Becky. I promise.
你没事吧？嗯
You okay? Yeah.
乖孩子
Good boy.
马特
Matt.
我们能行
We can make it.
所以 机长 你有没有一个不单靠运气的计划？
So, Captain, do you have a plan that doesn't rely on just dumb luck?
你知道我们都还活着
You know we're alive.
我们都还活着
We're all alive.
你有孩子吗？
You got kids?
有
Yeah.
我女儿泰瑞 小儿子肖恩 哦 我有三个孩子
My daughter Terri, my little boy Sean. Well, I got three.
最小的才五岁
Youngest is five.
我告诉你 他们长大不能没有我
I can tell you they ain't growing up without me.
所以 不管你做什么  来让自己对牺牲那么多人好受点
So whatever you gotta do to make yourself feel better about losing all those people back there,
但别拿我当借口 朋友
but don't use me, pal.
因为无论如何  我都要活着回家
Because I'm going home whatever it takes
是啊 我敢肯定你的孩子会为你感到骄傲 难怪你还是单身
Yeah, I am sure your kids are real proud of you. No wonder you're single
有飞机！
A plane
飞机来了！喂！喂！喂！喂！喂！喂！喂！喂！喂！
Plane is here. Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey
喂！
Hey
喂
在下面呢 你个混蛋
Down here, you asshole
喂 喂 喂
Hey, hey, hey
他们看见我们没？肯定看见了
Did they see us? They saw us all right
我们得撑住
We just gotta hold on
佐伊
Zoe
佐伊 佐伊
Zoe, Zoe
佐伊 快醒醒
Zoe, wake up
快来人啊
Somebody help
我亲爱的小贝拉
My dear little Bella
我也不知道我干嘛要这样
I don't know why I'm doing this
你永远都听不见我说话
You're never going to hear me
没信号了
There's no service
贝拉
Bella
我得和上帝聊聊
I'm going to have a little chat with God
求他让你的生活充满
and ask him to fill your life with as much
快乐
joy
就像你带给我的一样
as you've given me
关岛红尾24 运输进展如何？
Guam Red Tail 24 Any updates on the transport situation
正在解决 附近有艘中国拖网渔船
Working on it. We've got a Chinese trawler in the area.
红尾24待命 明白
Red Tail 24 standby. Copy that.
我是兴洋远渔08号
This is the i Xing Yang Yuan Yu 08
船长  我们正在根据1974年《国际海上人命安全公约》行动
Captain  We are enacting i i the 1974 SOLAS convention i i
有一架商用客机坠毁了
There's been i i a commercial airliner crash i i
你的船离那片区域最近
Your ship is closest i i to the area i i
我们推测那里可能有需要救援的幸存者 收到 指挥官
where we believe i i there are survivors i i in need of assistance i Copy Commander
什么？谢谢
What? Thank you.
直接跟她说吧
Just tell her
你特别喜欢她
That you're crazy about her
我不能破坏队里的规矩
I can't break team rules
什么规矩啊？
What team rule?
队员之间不能谈恋爱 老天 你也太傻了吧
Players cannot date each other. My God, you're such an idiot.
谁管那条规矩啊
No one listens to that rule
直接跟她说吧
Just tell her
嘿 科拉
Hey Cora
把这个喝了
Drink this
他们没在这儿
They're not here
嘿 他们把我扔下了
Hey, they left me
喝吧
Come on
他们没扔下你
They didn't leave you
我爸让我照看我弟
My dad told me to look after my little brother
我以前做得太糟了
I was horrible
我不讨厌他
I don't hate him
我知道
I know
他七岁
He's seven
我儿子七岁
My son is seven
右边那个是肖恩
That's Sean there on the right
他哪有七岁？
He's not seven
那是旧照片了
It's an old picture
唉 他们再也看不到我长大后的样子了
Hmm. They'll never get to see how I turn out
嘿 他们知道的
Hey, they'll know
父母什么都知道
Parents always know
他们从未离开过你 科拉
They're always with you, Cora
哦！天哪！
Oh yes. Oh my God
天哪！嘿！天哪！他们要来救我们了！哈奇 看好科拉 这边！嘿 我们在这儿！
Oh my God. Oh hey. Oh my God. They're gonna rescue us. Hutch, look after Cora. Over here. Hey, we're here
关岛红尾24 发现幸存者
Guam Red Tail 24 we have survivors
投放照明弹 救援人员下水
Dropping flares and putting swimmer in the water
救援人员准备下水
Deploy swimmer
嘿
Hey
不 我们在舱门边 收到 准备就绪
No, we're at the door. Copy that. Good to go.
不
No
我们看到你了
We see you
别 别
No, no
不
No
我拉不动 往上拉 往上拉！
I can't pull us up. Up, up, up!
红尾24 你们没事吧？
Red Tail 24, everything all right?
我的天哪
Oh my God
快割断它！快割断它！
Cut it loose! Cut it loose!
快拉我上去！快拉我上去！把你的手给我！
Get me out! Get me out of the water! Give me your hand!
快拉我出去
Get me out
快带我离开这儿
Get me out of here
不
No
畜生
Bastard
嘿 嘿 我在这儿 嘿 嘿
Hey, hey, I'm here. Hey, hey.
他们怎么停了？
Why'd they stop?
他们怎么停船了？
他们被礁石挡住了
They can't get past the reef.
我们得过去帮他们 怎么过去？桨呢？
We need to go to them. How? Where are the paddles?
我们没有桨 桨全没了 那现在怎么办 机长？
We don't have any paddles. We have no paddles. So what now, Captain?
水流会把我们冲进深海 嘿！
The current will carry us to the deep water. Hey!
别的筏子有桨 它们能到岸
The other rafts, they've got paddles. They'll make it.
科拉呢？
Where's Cora?
那个小女孩科拉 科拉！科拉！科拉！
The little girl Cora. Cora! Cora! Cora!
她掉水里了吗？科拉！科拉！
Is she in the water? Cora! Cora!
她在那边 那儿！快看 快看！
There she is. There! Look, look!
嘿 科拉！科拉 别动！
Hey, Cora! Cora, stay there!
科拉 科拉 我们得去救她 水流太急了
Cora, Cora, we have to go get her. The current's too strong.
另一只筏子快靠岸了
Well, the other raft's nearly there.
那架飞机15分钟后就掉水里了
That plane's going to be in the water in 15 minutes.
好吧 我去救她 有鲨鱼！你疯了吗？
All right, I'm gonna get her. The sharks. Are you crazy?
到处都是鲨鱼 不 这是你的船 嘿 别 等等！
They're everywhere. No, it's your boat. Hey, no, wait!
不！
No!
快游！再快点！他能游到！他快成功了！
Swim fast! Swim faster! He can make it! He's gonna make it!
救命啊！
Help me!
我是美国人
I am an American.
他做到了！太棒了！太棒了！
He made it! Yes! Yes!
科拉 嘿 科拉 看看我
Cora, hey Cora, look at me.
嘿 科拉 我们一起去游泳 你和我 一起
Hey Cora, we're gonna go for a swim. Together. You and me.
我要和我爸爸待在一起
I want to stay here with my daddy.
你不能待在这儿 科拉
You can't stay here, Cora.
我们得绕点路 好吗？
We gotta take a little detour, okay?
水涨上来了 科拉 你爸爸希望你做个勇敢的女孩 好吗？
The water's rising, Cora. Your daddy wants you to be a brave girl, okay?
好 来 把这个穿上
All right, let's put this on you.
好了 穿好了
Okay. There you go.
我们会没事的 科拉
We're gonna be all right Cora
我们能行 好吗？
We got this okay
我要把这根带子绕过脖子 系到背后 好吗？
I'm gonna put this belt on over my neck around my back okay
等会儿游泳的时候 你要抓牢它 好吗？
And I want you to hold onto it while we swim All right
你千万不能松手 知道吗？一定要抓紧了 嘿 我们漂远了
You're not gonna let go of this okay You hold on tight Okay Hey we're drifting away
我们漂远了 离他们越来越远了 方向错了 笨蛋！往船那边游！
We're drifting away we're drifting away from them Wrong way dumbass To the boat
快抓住带子 科拉 抓紧了！
Grab the belt Cora Grab it
有鲨鱼！有鲨鱼！
Shark Shark
他们全跑了
They all left
他们怎么走了？
Why'd they go
鬼才知道
God only knows
没事没事 都会好的 他们应该走了 我们安全了
It's okay it's okay Everything's okay It's gonna be okay I think they're gone We'll be okay
嗯
Yeah
你个混蛋
You son of a bitch
来 科拉 把这个披上
Here Cora, let's put this around you
绕了点路 是吧？
A little detour, huh?
嗯
Yeah
是绕了点路
A little detour
嘿 嘿 有信号了！本 有信号了！手机能用了
Hey, hey, we got a signal. We got reception, Ben. We got reception. The phones are working.
宠物芯片 你的手机呢？
The pet chip. Your phone.
你能看到你的手机吗？
Can you see your phone?
我能看看吗？
Can I see it?
密码是他生日
Password's his birthday.
你看 看到了吧
There. See.
多谢了 船长
Thank you Captain
我们感激你的船员为我们做的一切 谢谢  木筏在那边
We owe your crew for everything you've done for us. Thank you. SPEAKING CHINESE Raft Over there
我弟弟呢？他肯定在这儿
Where's my brother? He's gotta be here
追踪器显示他在这儿
The tracker says he's here
芬恩 对不起 科拉
Finn, I'm sorry, Cora
芬恩！
Finn
芬恩 芬恩 佐伊 芬恩 芬恩 芬恩 我们成功了
Finn, Finn, Zoe, Finn, Finn, Finn. We made it,
科拉 芬恩 芬恩 来 你在这儿
Cora. Finn, Finn. Come on. There you go
对不起
I'm sorry
没事的 科拉
It's okay, Cora
翻译 字幕 校轴：无心睡眠
贝基 贝基 她在等我
Becky, Becky. She's waiting for me
来 我们把她扶起来
Come on, let's get her up
本 是我 天哪 你还好吗？ 还好
Ben, it's me. Oh my God. Are you okay?  Yeah
我以为你出事了 我没事 本
I thought we lost you. I'm okay. Ben
让我跟他说话 肖恩
Let me talk to him. Sean
天哪
Oh my God
爸正在通话中
Dad's on the phone right now
爸爸 你在吗？我在 肖恩 我在这儿
Daddy, are you there? I'm here, Sean. I'm right here
你在哪儿？
Where are you?
我要回家了 妈 他要回家了
I'm coming home. Mom, he's coming home.
他要回来了
He's coming home.
我早说过他会回来的 宝贝
I told you he would, darling.
我爱你 爸
I love you, Dad.
我也爱你 儿子
I love you too, son.
我爱你们大家
I love all of you.